(CITRA SEKAR PANDITA, 30 y.o) (QA ENGINEER)

(Bogor) | (081228759075) | (citrasekaripb@gmail.com) (https://www.linkedin.com/in/citra-sekar-pandita-425887157/)

PROFILE

A QA Engineer with 5 years of experience. Familiar with web-based, mobile-based and API Testing as QA Engineer. Also experience in automation testing using Katalon studio and Postman for less than 1 year. Experience working in multiple project as main QA for 3-4 projects in Bank BRI and PT Bluebird Group. Dedicated, fast learning, detail oriented, and has a speed.

EXPERIENCE

PT SARANG GAGAK SAKTI – Jakarta, Indonesia

QA Engineer (Mar 2024 – Aug 2024)

- Performing reggression testing, sanity test, smoke test, usability test Project Web Solos on desktop, mobile view in desktop and mobile phone
- Create scenario and test case with Testrail as management test case tools
- Create scenario and test case with Qase.io as management test case tools
- Bug reporting , bug evidence, manage task, timeline with Notion

PT BLUEBIRD GROUP - Jakarta, Indonesia

QA Engineer (May 2021- Feb 2024)

- Working with Agile Methodology with Jira as Management tools
- Responsible as main and only QA at Squad API Gateway, Bengkel, BBONE
- Responsible as QA team at squad promo portal marketing and Golden bird
- Create ticket bug and epic with Jira
- Performing manual testing such smoke test, sanity test, regression test, usability test, user acceptance test for web desktop, mobile web, mobile apps, IOT
- Performing manual testing for Bluebird Dispatch integrated by Vini Web, IoT, Driver Apps and MyBlueBird Apps
- Performing manual testing for Promo Portal at MyBB Portal Web, MyBlueBird Apps and Appsflyer web for IOS
- Performing manual testing for Golden Bird at Golden Bird Apps, Golden Reservasi Pusat Web, API Price Engine, API Golden Bird Reservasi Pusat
- Performing manual testing for Bengkel Web integrated to Driver Apps ,Mobil Jual Web and API of transaction payment and price order , BBONE Personalia Web, Area Management and Operational Application Web and driver recruitment mobile web Regression testing APIGW order partner in API to driver apps and IOT in env regress
- Create activity diagram for Promo Portal Web
- Create scenario and test case SIT, TC, deployment, regression and sprint on TestLink management tools and spreadsheet
- Manual and automation API Testing with Postman API Gateway Partners such Gojek, Shopee, Traveloka etc and API Testing with BloomRPC GUI Client for GRPC Service and Postman

PT BANK BRI PERSERO, TBK- Jakarta, Indonesia

QA Engineer (Sep 2019 - Apr 2021)

- Responsible as main and only QA for three projects Delima Web, BRIPHONE apps and Ambilin mobile web
- Working with Agile methodology with Jira and Trello as management tools
- Performing API testing with POSTMAN and INSOMNIA for Delima Web and BRIPHONE apps
- Performing manual testing such smoke test, sanity test, regression test, usability test, user acceptance test for Delima web, BRIPHONE apps and Ambilin mobile web
- Create test scenario and test case using spreadsheet for Delima Web and BRIPHONE apps
- Create test scenario and test case using test case management tool (Qase.io) for Ambilin mobile web
- Create automation test using Katalon Studio for Ambilin mobile web and BRIPHONE apps

IPB UNIVERSITY

Assistant Lecturer IT (May 2016 – May 2019)

- Monitoring and co-assistant lecturer to help student in computer practice class for subject Computer Application, Programming Language, Mobile Programming, Web Programming, Data Structure and Algorithm and Programming
- Co-teaching in practice class
- Grading assigments and exams

EDUCATION

GUNADARMA UNIVERSITY (2016-2018)

Bachelor of Informatics System

IPB UNIVERSITY (2012-2015)

Diploma of Informatics Management

HARD SKILLS

- Excellence at working Agile using Scrum Methodologies such JIRA and Trello
- Excellence at manual testing in web, mobile web, android mobile app, IOT
- Excellence at automation testing with Katalon Studio, Postman, Cypress
- Experience at automation testing with TestNG, Ruby, Java, Appium
- Excellence at testcase management tools with Testrail, Qase.io, Testlink
- Experience at stress testing with Jmeter
- Excellence at testcase management tools with Qase.io, testlink, manual spreadsheet
- Good writing and speaking in English
- Good at basic SQL Query

SOFT SKILLS

- Detail orientation
- Highly motivated
- Analytical skills
- Fast learning
- Highly organized
- Dedicated, loyal
- Hard worker
- Big curiosity to learn
- Good teamwork

TRAINING

- Quality Assurance, 2024, Sanber Code IT Bootcamp
- Quality Assurance of Automation, 2024, Sanber Code IT Bootcamp
- Introduction To Role: Product Manager, 2022, Titik Balik
- Learning Product Management, 2022, Titik Balik
- Katalon Studio For Automated Testing, 2020, Hacktiv8 Indonesia
- PCAP:Programming Essentials in Python, 2020, Cisco Networking Academy Course
- Hybrid: Build Once, Deploy Anywhere Basic Fundamental, 2020, PT Hideki Maxima Utama
- STLC Guidance For Manual QA Essential of Software Quality Assurance, 2020, QADEMY
- Introduction To Rest API Testing Using POSTMAN, 2020, QADEMY
- Basic Automation Web With JS, 2020, ATLAS
- Basic Java Class, 2020, ATLAS
- Automation Testing Ruby Basic Class, 2020, ATLAS
- How To Write Good Test Design (Test coverage, matrix traceability, 2020 test scenario, requirement analysis), 2020, QADEMY
- How To Write Good Test Cases, 2020, QADEMY
- Belajar Dasar Pemograman Web, 2019, Dicoding
- Google Cloud Platform Fundamentals: Core Infrastructure Course, 2019, Google Artificial Intelligence, 2019, Digital Talent Scholarship Kominfo